<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <system>Firefox</system>
  <release>28.0<features><feature>VP9 video decoding implemented</feature><feature>Mac OS X: Notification Center support for web notifications</feature><feature>Horizontal HTML5 audio/video volume control</feature><feature>Support for Opus in WebM</feature></features></release>
  <release>29.0<features><feature>Significant new customization mode makes it easy to personalize your Web experience to access the features you use the most (learn more)</feature><feature>A new, easy to access menu sits in the right hand corner of Firefox and includes popular browser controls</feature><feature>Sleek new tabs provide an overall smoother look and fade into the background when not active</feature><feature>An interactive onboarding tour to guide users through the new Firefox changes</feature><feature>The ability to set up Firefox Sync by creating a Firefox account (learn more)</feature><feature>Gamepad API finalized and enabled</feature><feature>HTTPS used for Yahoo Searches performed in en-US locale</feature><feature>Malay [ma] locale added</feature></features></release>
  <release>30.0<features><feature>Sidebars button in browser chrome enables faster access to social, bookmark, &amp; history sidebars</feature><feature>Mac OS X command-E sets find term to selected text</feature></features></release>
  <release>31.0<features><feature>Add the search field to the new tab page</feature><feature>Support of Prefer:Safe http header for parental control (learn more)</feature><feature>mozilla::pkix as default certificate verifier (learn more)</feature><feature>Partial implementation of the OpenType MATH table (section 6.3.6) see documentation about mathematical fonts and the MathML Torture Test for details</feature><feature>Block malware from downloaded files (learn more)</feature><feature>audio/video .ogg and .pdf files handled by Firefox if no application specified (Windows only)</feature><feature>Upper Sorbian [hsb] locale added</feature></features></release>
  <release>32.0<features><feature>New HTTP cache provides improved performance including crash recovery</feature><feature>Integration of generational garbage collection</feature><feature>Public key pinning support enabled</feature><feature>View historical use information for logins stored in password manager</feature><feature>Display the number of found items in the find toolbar </feature><feature>Easier back, forward, reload, and bookmarking through the context menu</feature><feature>Lower Sorbian [dsb] locale added</feature></features></release>
  <release>33.0<features><feature>OpenH264 support (sandboxed)</feature><feature>Improved search experience through the location bar</feature><feature>Windows: OMTC enabled by default</feature><feature>Slimmer and faster JavaScript strings</feature><feature>Search suggestions on the Firefox Start (about:home) and new tab (about:newtab) pages</feature><feature>Support for connecting to HTTP proxy over HTTPS</feature><feature>New CSP (Content Security Policy) backend</feature><feature>Improved reliability of the session restoration</feature><feature>Azerbaijani [az] locale added</feature></features></release>
  <release>34.0<features><feature>Default search engine changed to Yandex for Belarusian, Kazakh, and Russian locales</feature><feature>Improved search bar (en-US only)</feature><feature>Firefox Hello real-time communication client</feature><feature>Easily switch themes/personas directly in the Customizing mode</feature><feature>Wikipedia search now uses HTTPS for secure searching (en-US only)</feature><feature>Recover from a locked Firefox process in the "Firefox is already running" dialog on Windows</feature></features></release>
  <release>35.0<features><feature>Firefox Hello with new rooms-based conversations model</feature><feature>New search UI improved and enabled for more locales</feature><feature>Access the Firefox Marketplace from the Tools menu and optional toolbar button</feature><feature>Built-in support for H264 (MP4) on Mac OS X Snow Leopard (10.6) and newer through native APIs</feature><feature>Improved handling of dynamic styling changes to increase responsiveness</feature><feature>Use tiled rendering on OS X</feature><feature>Improved high quality image resizing performance</feature></features></release>
  <release>36.0<features><feature>Pinned tiles on the new tab page can be synced</feature><feature>Support for the full HTTP/2 protocol. HTTP/2 enables a faster, more scalable, and more responsive web.</feature><feature>Locale added: Uzbek (uz)</feature></features></release>
  <release>37.0<features><feature>Heartbeat user rating system - your feedback about Firefox</feature><feature>Yandex set as default search provider for the Turkish locale</feature><feature>Bing search now uses HTTPS for secure searching </feature><feature>Improved protection against site impersonation via OneCRL centralized certificate revocation</feature><feature>Opportunistically encrypt HTTP traffic where the server supports HTTP/2 AltSvc</feature></features></release>
  <release>38.0<features><feature>New tab-based preferences</feature><feature>Ruby annotation support</feature><feature>Base for the next ESR release.</feature></features></release>
  <release>39.0<features><feature>Share Hello URLs with social networks</feature><feature>Project Silk: Smoother animation and scrolling (Mac OS X)</feature><feature>Support for 'switch' role in ARIA 1.1 (web accessibility)</feature><feature>SafeBrowsing malware detection lookups enabled for downloads (Mac OS X and Linux)</feature><feature>Support for new Unicode 8.0 skin tone emoji </feature></features></release>
  <release>40.0<features><feature>Support for Windows 10</feature><feature>Added protection against unwanted software downloads</feature><feature>User can receive suggested tiles in the new tab page based on categories Firefox matches to browsing history (en-US only).</feature><feature>Hello allows adding a link to conversations to provide context on what the conversation will be about</feature><feature>New style for add-on manager based on the in-content preferences style</feature><feature>Improved scrolling, graphics, and video playback performance with off main thread compositing (GNU/Linux only)</feature><feature>Graphic blocklist mechanism improved: Firefox version ranges can be specified, limiting the number of devices blocked</feature></features></release>
  <release>41.0<features><feature>SVG images can be used as favicons</feature><feature>Enhance IME support on Windows (Vista +) using TSF (Text Services Framework)</feature><feature>Ability to set a profile picture for your Firefox Account</feature><feature>Firefox Hello now includes instant messaging</feature><feature>Improved box-shadow rendering performance</feature></features></release>
  <release>42.0<features><feature>Private Browsing with Tracking Protection blocks certain Web elements that could be used to record your behavior across sites</feature><feature>Control Center that contains site security and privacy controls</feature><feature>Indicator added to tabs that play audio with one-click muting</feature><feature>Login Manager improvements:</feature><feature>WebRTC improvements:</feature></features></release>
  <release>43.0<features><feature>Private Browsing with Tracking Protection offers choice of blocking additional trackers</feature><feature>Improved API support for m4v video playback</feature><feature>Firefox 64-bit for Windows is now available via the Firefox download page</feature><feature>Users can choose search suggestions from the Awesome Bar</feature><feature>On-screen keyboard displayed on selecting input field on devices running Windows 8 or greater</feature><feature>Firefox Health Report has switched to use the same data collection mechanism as telemetry</feature></features></release>
  <release>44.0<features><feature>Improved warning pages for certificate errors and untrusted connections</feature><feature>Enable H.264 if system decoder is available</feature><feature>Enable WebM/VP9 video support on systems that don't support MP4/H.264</feature><feature>In the animation-inspector timeline, lightning bolt icon next to animations running on the compositor thread</feature><feature>Support the brotli compression format via HTTPS content-encoding</feature><feature>Screenshot commands allow user choice of pixel ratio in Developer Tools</feature><feature>Firefox can now get Push Notifications from your favorite sites</feature></features></release>
  <release>45.0<features><feature>Instant browser tab sharing through Hello</feature><feature>Tabs synced via Firefox Accounts from other devices are now shown in dropdown area of Awesome Bar when searching</feature><feature>Synced Tabs button in button bar</feature><feature>Introduce a new preference (network.dns.blockDotOnion) to allow blocking .onion at the DNS level</feature><feature>Guarani [gn] locale added</feature></features></release>
  <release>46.0<features><feature>Improved security of the JavaScript Just In Time (JIT) Compiler</feature><feature>GTK3 integration (GNU/Linux only)</feature></features></release>
  <release>47.0<features><feature>Support for Google’s Widevine CDM on Windows and Mac OS X so streaming services like Amazon Video can switch from Silverlight to encrypted HTML5 video.</feature><feature>Enable VP9 video codec for users with fast machines</feature><feature>Embedded YouTube videos now play with HTML5 video if Flash is not installed.</feature><feature>Allow no-cache on back/forward navigations for https resources</feature><feature>Latgalu [ltg] locale added. Wikipedia tells us there are 164,500 daily speakers.</feature><feature>View and search open tabs from your smartphone or another computer in a sidebar</feature></features></release>
  <release>48.0<features><feature>Process separation (e10s) is enabled for some of you. Like it? Let us know and we'll roll it out to more</feature><feature>Roar for moar protection against harmful downloads! We've got your back</feature><feature>Add-ons that have not been verified and signed by Mozilla will not load</feature><feature>GNU/Linux fans: Get better Canvas performance with speedy Skia support. Try saying that three times fast</feature><feature>Windows folks: Tab (move buttons) and Shift+F10 (pop-up menus) now behave as they should in Firefox customization mode</feature><feature>Searching for something already in your bookmarks or open tabs? We added super smart icons to let you know</feature><feature>WebRTC embetterments:</feature><feature>Windows 7 systems without Platform Update can now use D3D11 WARP</feature><feature>The media parser has been redeveloped using the Rust programming language</feature></features></release>
  <release>49.0<features><feature>Updated Firefox Login Manager to allow HTTPS pages to use saved HTTP logins. It’s one more way Firefox is supporting Let’s Encrypt and helping users transition to a more secure web.</feature><feature>Added features to Reader Mode that make it easier on the eyes and the ears</feature><feature>Improved video performance for users on systems that support SSSE3 without hardware acceleration</feature><feature>Added context menu controls to HTML5 audio and video that let users loops files or play files at 1.25x speed</feature><feature>Enhancements for Mac users </feature><feature>Improvements in about:memory reports for tracking font memory usage</feature><feature>Improve performance on Windows systems without hardware acceleration</feature><feature>Support of Widevine CDM through the EME API under GNU/Linux</feature></features></release>
  <release>50.0<features><feature>Updates to keyboard shortcuts</feature><feature>Added option to Find in page that allows users to limit search to whole words only</feature><feature>Added Guarani (gn) locale</feature><feature>Increased availability of WebGL to more than 98 percent of users on Windows 7 and newer</feature><feature>Added download protection for a large number of executable file types on Windows, Mac and Linux</feature><feature>Improved performance for SDK extensions or extensions using the SDK module loader</feature><feature>Playback video on more sites without plugins with WebM EME Support for Widevine on Windows and Mac</feature></features></release>
  <release>51.0<features><feature>Added support for FLAC (Free Lossless Audio Codec) playback</feature><feature>Users can view passwords in the save password prompt before saving them</feature><feature>Added a zoom button in the URL bar: </feature><feature>Improved video performance for users without GPU acceleration for less CPU usage and a better full screen experience</feature><feature>Firefox will save passwords even in forms that do not have “submit” events </feature><feature>Added support for WebGL 2, with advanced graphics rendering features like transform feedback, improved texturing capabilities, and a new sophisticated shading language</feature><feature>A warning is displayed when a login page does not have a secure connection</feature><feature>Added Georgian (ka) and Kabyle (kab) locales</feature><feature>An even faster E10s! Tab Switching is better!</feature><feature>Improved reliability of browser data sync</feature><feature>Remove Belarusian (be) locale</feature></features></release>
  <release>52.0<features><feature>Added support for WebAssembly, an emerging standard that brings near-native performance to Web-based games, apps, and software libraries without the use of plugins.</feature><feature>Added automatic captive portal detection, for easier access to Wi-Fi hotspots. When accessing the Internet via a captive portal, Firefox will alert users and open the portal login page in a new tab.</feature><feature>Enhanced Sync to allow users to send and open tabs from one device to another.</feature><feature>Added user warnings for non-secure HTTP pages with logins. Firefox now displays a “This connection is not secure” message when users click into the username and password fields on pages that don’t use HTTPS.</feature><feature>Implemented the Strict Secure Cookies specification which forbids insecure HTTP sites from setting cookies with the "secure" attribute.  In some cases, this will prevent an insecure site from setting a cookie with the same name as an existing "secure" cookie from the same base domain.</feature></features></release>
  <release>53.0<features><feature>Improved graphics stability for Windows users with the addition of compositor process separation (Quantum Compositor)</feature><feature>Two new 'compact' themes available in Firefox, dark and light, based on the Firefox Developer Edition theme</feature><feature>Lightweight themes are now applied in private browsing windows</feature><feature>Reader Mode now displays estimated reading time for the page</feature><feature>Windows 7+ users on 64-bit OS can select 32-bit or 64-bit versions in the stub installer</feature></features></release>
  <release>54.0<features><feature>Added Burmese (my) locale</feature><feature>Added support for multiple content processes (e10s-multi)</feature><feature>Simplified the download button and download status panel</feature></features></release>
  <release>55.0<features><feature>Launched Windows support for WebVR, bringing immersive experiences to the web. See examples and try working demos at Mozilla VR.</feature><feature>Added options that let users optimize recent performance improvements</feature><feature>Simplified installation process with a streamlined Windows stub installer</feature><feature>Improved address bar functionality</feature><feature>Updated Sidebar for bookmarks, history, and synced tabs so it can appear at the right edge of the window as well as the left</feature><feature>Added support for stereo microphones with WebRTC</feature><feature>Pages can be simplified before printing from within Print Preview</feature><feature>Updated Firefox for OSX and macOS to allow users to assign custom keyboard shortcuts to Firefox menu items via System Preferences </feature><feature>Browsing sessions with a high number of tabs are now restored in an instant</feature><feature>Make screenshots of webpages, and save them locally or upload them to the cloud. This feature will undergo A/B testing and will not be visible for some users.</feature><feature>Added Belarusian (be) locale</feature></features></release>
  <release>56.0<features><feature>Launched Firefox Screenshots, a feature that lets users take, save, and share screenshots without leaving the browser</feature><feature>Added support for address form autofill (en-US only)</feature><feature>Updated Preferences </feature><feature>Media opened in a background tab will not play until the tab is selected</feature><feature>Improved Send Tabs feature of Sync for iOS and Android, and Send Tabs can be discovered even by users without a Firefox Account</feature></features></release>
  <release>57.0<features><feature>A completely new browsing engine, designed to take full advantage of the processing power in modern devices</feature><feature>A redesigned interface with a clean, modern appearance, consistent visual elements, and optimizations for touch screens</feature><feature>A unified address and search bar. New installs will see this unified bar. Learn how to add the stand-alone search bar to the toolbar</feature><feature>A revamped new tab page that includes top visited sites, recently visited pages, and recommendations from Pocket (in the US, Canada, and Germany)</feature><feature>An updated product tour to orient new and returning Firefox users</feature><feature>Video decoding is shut down when the tab playing the media is sent to the background or the video is not visible on the screen. Video resumes when the media tab is in the foreground and the player is visible on the screen. Audio will not be affected.</feature><feature>AMD VP9 hardware video decoder support for improved video playback with lower power consumption</feature><feature>An expanded section in preferences to manage all website permissions</feature><feature>In case you missed it—57 Release privacy and performance feature:
Users can enable Tracking Protection at all times. Learn how to turn Tracking Protection on.</feature></features></release>
  <release>58.0<features><feature>Performance improvements, including:</feature><feature>Improvements to Firefox Screenshots:</feature><feature>Added Nepali (ne-NP) locale</feature><feature>In case you missed it—57 Release privacy and performance feature:
Users can enable Tracking Protection at all times. Learn how to turn Tracking Protection on.</feature></features></release>
  <release>59.0<features><feature>Performance enhancements:
 - Faster load times for content on the Firefox Home page
 - Faster page load times by loading either from the networked cache or the cache on the user’s hard drive (Race Cache With Network)
 - Improved graphics rendering using Off-Main-Thread Painting (OMTP) for Mac users (OMTP for Windows was released in Firefox 58)</feature><feature>Drag-and-drop to rearrange Top Sites on the Firefox Home page, and customize new windows and tabs in other ways</feature><feature>Added features for Firefox Screenshots:
 - Basic annotation lets the user draw on and highlight saved screenshots
 - Recropping to change the viewable area of saved screenshots</feature><feature>Enhanced WebExtensions API including better support for decentralized protocols and the ability to dynamically register content scripts</feature><feature>Improved Real-Time Communications (RTC) capabilities.
 - Implemented RTP Transceiver to give pages more fine grained control over calls
 - Implemented features to support large scale conferences</feature><feature>Added support for W3C specs for pointer events and improved platform integration with added device support for mouse, pen, and touch screen pointer input</feature><feature>Added the Ecosia search engine as an option for German Firefox</feature><feature>Added the Qwant search engine as an option for French Firefox</feature><feature>Added settings in about:preferences to stop websites from asking to send notifications or access your device’s camera, microphone, and location, while still allowing trusted websites to use these features</feature></features></release>
</root>
